

Rajesh Prasad Mob:-+91-9971050705 Email: - simplyRprasad@gmail.com

#### **SYNOPSIS**

MCA with 11 years of experience in Software Development on Microsoft Technologies.

An accomplished software programmer well versed in Object-Oriented Design and Analysis with extensive experience in the project SDLC including requirement definition, designing, coding, testing and maintenance.

### **Experience**

• May 2015 to till date Stefanini India Pvt Ltd. as Team Lead

Aug 2013 to May 2015 Remiel Softtech Solutions Pvt Ltd. as Tech Lead
Oct 2010 to July 2013 AlTechnology Pvt Ltd. as Senior Software Engineer

• Sep 2008 to Sep 2010 Secure Meter Ltd. as Excutive-3

• June 2006 to Aug 2008 Imfinity India Pvt Ltd. as Software Engineer

### Certification

• MCP (Microsoft Certified Professional) Developing and Implementing Web Application with Microsoft Visual C#.NET And Microsoft Visual Studio.NET.

## **Technical Knowledge**

• Technologies : C# with .Net 2.0/4.0/4.5, MVC4, Entity Framework, LINQ, Asp.Net,

WebApi, WCF, Web Service, and nHibernate.

Scripting Language : Angular JS/JQuery/JavaScript.

Tools : Visual studio 2005-15, SVN/TFS/VSS/CVS and Trello.
Databases : SQL-Server 2008/2012, Oracle and SQL Developer.

# **Educational Qualification**

MCA from IGNOU 2007

• BCA from IGNOU 2004

### **Notable Project**

Project Title : Logistic Management System (LMS)

Client : Ryder, U.S.A

**Environment**: Asp.Net MVC, C#, LINQ, SQL Server 2012, nHibernate, AngularJS, Web API,

Trello and TFS.

**Team Size :** 5 **Role/Responsibilities:** 

Developed the Web API for business logic and database interaction.

- Worked in Agile environment, attending daily scrum meetings and used Trello for Sprint.
- Taken part in the setup the project in our environment.
- Done unit testing of the software developed.
- Participate and provide input in code optimization and performance related discussions.
- Participate in client discussion to understand the project requirement.

**Description**: Ryder, is an American-based provider of transportation and supply chain management products, and is especially known for its fleet of rental trucks. The objective of this project is to update existing functionality and developed new functionality by implementing Web API for schedule, reschedule and cancel the appointments. Some appointments uploaded by Bulk uploader.

Project Title : Extract Surge Project Client : Retail Data, LLC, U.S.A

**Environment**: Asp.Net MVC, C#, LINQ, SQL Server 2012, JQuery, Entity Framework, TFS

**Team Size** : 6 **Role/Responsibilities** :

- Have regular discussion with on-site Tech Lead to understand the project requirement and tasks.
- Configure the Extracts with reference from old system to new system.
- Written code related to business logic and database interaction.
- Worked extensively with LINQ, Entity Framework.
- Generate the reports and made some changes into code to match reports from old to new system.
- Worked in Agile environment, attending daily scrum meetings.
- Worked for code optimization and performance related changes.

**Description**: The objective of this project is to revamp existing Extract Engine and all the associated extracts (about 500), to serve the Client Services efficiently, and in standard manner. Extract is basically a profile based on some search criteria to get reports through which client analyse their products. Here Extract Engine fetch base records based on some configuration and further configuration options help to build and generate the report. This project also aims at complete migration of "Extract Data" from Progress to SQL Server 2012.

Project Title : DAMES Local Portal

Client : LG

**Environment**: MVC4, C#, Oracle 11g and WCF Service

Team Size : 2

Role/Responsibilities: Writing business logic and business rules and handle UI integration. Developing

functions, procedures and other objects to implement the system's business logic using SQL.

**Description**: This portal provides facilities to Production department for various types of Master data and their report. It provides facility to user to edit the production data to run smoothly production of various product of LG. This portal also generates different type of report in excel formats.

Project Title : EDI Portal Client : LG and Reliance

URL : http://202.154.175.31:1100/EDIPortalLogin.aspx

**Environment**: Asp.Net, C#, Oracle 11g and WCF Service

Team Size : 4 Role/Responsibilities:

- Writing business logic and business rules and handle UI integration.
- Coordinating with manager along with client to understand the business requirement of the project.
- Creating and consuming the WCF services to communicate with the remote server for data transfer.

**Description**: This portal provides facilities to Modern trade to exchange their information by Electronic Data Interchange. Here Reliance (Modern Trade) sends Purchase Order via WCF service to EDI Portal. This Portal generates the Invoice based on Purchase Order or Reject the Purchase Order. EDI Portal sends the invoice details to Reliance and receives ASN No as an acknowledgement. This ASN No and order send to Reliance warehouse. This portal also generates different type of report in excel formats.

Project Title : GMI Mobile Application Development

**Client** : General Mills

**Environment**: MVC3.0, C#, WCF and SQL Server 2008

Team Size : 5

**Responsibilities**: Writing business logic and business rules and handle UI integration. Creating and consuming the WCF services to communicate with the remote server for data transfer.

**Description**: The scope of the work will involve developing a Standalone HTML5 App and a Basic Content Management System (CMS) to manage the contents of the HTML5 App for General Mills. The application will be developed for General Mills Sales Team and will be an interactive survey that will guide the user to the correct continuous improvement (CI) tool needed to help them solve their business problems.

Project Title : SAP Benchmarking

Client : SAP India

**Environment**: Asp.Net 3.5, C#, Web Services and SQL Server 2008

Team Size : 14

Role/Responsibilities: Writing business logic and business rules for different module like optimization of

CType, PType calculation and KPI engine functionality.

**Description**: The benchmarking procedure is standardized and well defined. It is monitored by the SAP benchmark council made up of representatives of SAP and technology partners Involved in benchmarking. Originally introduced to strengthen quality assurance, the SAP Standard Application Benchmarks can also be used to test and verify scalability, Concurrency, power efficiency, and multi-user behaviour of system software components, RDBMS, and business applications. This project contains different surveys and based on survey's response graph and other data are displayed. A vast calculation engine is associated with it.

Project Title : SAA (System Analysis and Audit)

Client : APDRP

**Environment**: Asp.Net 2.0, C#, WCF and Oracle9i

Team Size : 10

**Role/Responsibilities:** Designing LLD and HLD, writing business logic and business rules and handle UI

integration.

**Description**: SAA (System Analysis and Audit) is being designed as part of Strategic Product development for Revenue Management System complying with the APDRP Norms as published by Power ministry of India to provide an automated system for Energy Accounting and loss assessment in Power Distribution systems through meter data acquisition and network documentation. The solution helps to determine the loss in the entire electricity supply chain, from generation to the end user and hence measure the energy gap at strategic points throughout the network.

Project Title : Biz/ed Share Products

**Environment**: Asp.Net 2.0, C#, WCF and SQL Server 2005

Team Size : 5

**Role/Responsibilities:** Developing functions, procedures and other objects to implement the system's

business logic using SQL.

**Description**: Biz/ed Share Products is online business education sector in which educator and student will participate. This application divided in several products based upon general business related topic areas and the ability to share content and files. Application will allow the user to enter the system at a high level and view a list of communities. The user will also be able to see a list of products which are accessible to that particular user or institution. Users will either belong to an institution or be regarded as individuals. The additional product subscription offering will offer search and retrieval of video clips, case studies and additional class room materials for browsing and downloading.

### **Personal Details**

Date of Birth : 22<sup>nd</sup> Oct 1984 Marital status : Married Passport No : H9632578